Guide to the Records of the Theatre Arts Department, University of Pittsburgh Johnstown, 1973- UPJ.2010.01
ULS Johnstown
Records of the Theatre Arts Department, University of Pittsburgh Johnstown
1973
ULS Johnstown
UPJ.2010.01
7.2 Linear Feet 19 binders and 3 boxes
The Records of the Theatre Arts Department at the University of Pittsburgh Johnstown consist of stage production photographs, rehearsal photographs, stage production videos, rehearsal videos, stage production programs, newspaper clippings, marketing materials, and production notes for performances produced by the University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown's Theatre Arts Department, dating from 1973 to present.
Scope and Content Notes
The Records of the Theatre Arts Department consist of stage production photographs, rehearsal photographs, stage production videos, rehearsal videos, stage production programs, newspaper clippings, marketing materials, and production notes dating from 1973 to present. Newspaper clippings, marketing materials, production notes, and production videos are few. The records are arranged in chronological order and housed separately by medium type.
Access Restrictions
No restrictions.
Related Material
Concerts and Assemblies, Information Files, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
Dramatics Club, Information Files, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
Theatre Department, Information Files, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
The Advocate, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
The Panther, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
The Panther Cub, Pitt-Johnstown University Archives, Owen Library, University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
Accruals
Donations are added to the collection every year. These donations come from the Theatre Arts Department and Owen Library staff. If you are interested in donating materials to the collection, please contact the Archives & Special Collections staff.
Theater - study and teaching - Pennsylvania - Johnstown; Performing arts - study and teaching - Pennsylvania - Johnstown; College theatre - Pennsylvania - Johnstown; College and school drama, American - Pennsylvania - Johnstown; University of Pittsburgh at Johnstown
- Photographs, I.
  Scope and Content Notes
  This series of photographs is arranged in chronological order and housed by medium type (photographs, slides, contact sheets and negatives, or photographs saved to compact discs). They contain stage production photos and rehearsal photos.
  - West Side Story, February-March 1973 (Binder 1, Folder 1)
  - Passing Through from Exotic Places, April 1978 (Binder 1, Folder 2)
  - The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, October-November 1978 (Binder 1, Folder 3)
  - The House of Blue Leaves, February-March 1979 (Binder 1, Folder 4)
  - The Miracle Worker, Spring 1979 (Binder 1, Folder 5)
  - Mother Courage and Her Children, October 1979 (Binder 1, Folder 6)
  - Mother Courage and Her Children, October 1979 (Binder 16, Folder 1)
  - LuAnn Hampton Laverty Oberlander, February-March 1980bbb (Binder 1, Folder 7)
  - Merton of the Movies, June 1980 (Binder 1, Folder 8)
  - Merton of the Movies, June 1980 (Binder 16, Folder 2)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, October 1980 (Binder 2, Folder 1)
  - The Cherry Orchard, February 1981 (Binder 2, Folder 2)
  - The Cherry Orchard, February 1981 (Binder 16, Folder 3)
  - Bare Boards and Passion, May 1981 (Binder 2, Folder 3)
  - Bare Boards and Passion, May 1981 (Binder 16, Folder 4)
  - The Journey of the Fifth Horse, October 1981 (Binder 3, Folder 1)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, October 1982 (Binder 3, Folder 2)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, October 1982 (Binder 7, Folder 1)
  - The Royal Family, February-March 1983 (Binder 3, Folder 3)
  - Absurdity and Other Virtues, February-March 1985 (Binder 3, Folder 4)
  - Absurdity and Other Virtues, February-March 1985 (Binder 16, Folder 5)
  - Crimes of the Heart, June 1985 (Binder 16, Folder 6)
  - The Imaginary Invalid, November 1985 (Binder 4, Folder 1)
  - The Imaginary Invalid, November 1985 (Binder 16, Folder 7)
  - Cry of Players, February-March 1986 (Binder 16, Folder 8)
  - Wait Until Dark, June 1986 (Binder 4, Folder 2)
  - Wait Until Dark, June 1986 (Binder 16, Folder 9)
  - DA, Fall 1986 (Binder 16, Folder 10)
  - Arms of the Man, Spring 1987 (Binder 16, Folder 11)
  - Remains, June 1987 (Binder 4, Folder 3)
  - Remains, June 1987 (Binder 16, Folder 12)
  - Our Town, October-November 1987 (Binder 4, Folder 4)
  - Our Town, October-November 1987 (Binder 16, Folder 13)
  - The Dining Room, February 1988 (Binder 4, Folder 5)
  - The Dining Room, February 1988 (Binder 16, Folder 14)
  - The Sea Gull, June 1988 (Binder 4, Folder 6)
  - The Sea Gull, June 1988 (Binder 16, Folder 15)
  - Tartuffe, October-November 1988 (Binder 4, Folder 7)
  - Boundaries of Tennessee, February 1989 (Binder 4, Folder 8)
  - What Every Woman Knows, October 1989 (Binder 4, Folder 9)
  - The Diary of Anne Frank, February 1990 (Binder 10, Folder 10)
  - The Diary of Anne Frank, February 1990 (Binder 16, Folder 16)
  - The Citizens of Johnstown vs. the South Fork Fishing and Hunting Club, September 1889, May-June 1990 (Binder 4, Folder 11)
  - Hay Fever, October-November 1990 (Binder 4, Folder 12)
  - Hay Fever, October-November 1990 (Binder 16, Folder 17)
  - Dark of the Moon, February 1991 (Binder 4, Folder 13)
  - Quartermaine's Terms, May-June 1991 (Binder 4, Folder 14)
  - The Tempest, October-November 1991 (Binder 5, Folder 1)
  - The Tempest, October-November 1991 (Binder 16, Folder 18)
  - Three Sisters, February-March 1992 (Binder 5, Folder 2)
  - Three Sisters, February-March 1992 (Binder 16, Folder 19)
  - She Stoops to Conquer, October 1992 (Binder 5, Folder 3)
  - Cabaret, February 1993 (Binder 5, Folder 4)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, June 1993 (Binder 5, Folder 5)
  - Cat on a Hot Tin Roof, June 1993 (Binder 16, Folder 20)
  - As You Like It, October 1993 (Binder 5, Folder 6)
  - As You Like It, October 1993 (Binder 16, Folder 21)
  - Fire Over Water, June 1994 (Binder 5, Folder 7)
  - Fire Over Water, June 1994 (Binder 7, Folder 2)
  - Brighton Beach Memoirs, October 1994 (Binder 5, Folder 8)
  - Brighton Beach Memoirs, October 1994 (Binder 7, Folder 3)
  - Joe Egg, A Day in the Death of, February 1995 (Binder 5, Folder 9)
  - Joe Egg, A Day in the Death of, February 1995 (Binder 7, Folder 4)
  - Into the Woods, Spring 1995 (Binder 5, Folder 10)
  - Into the Woods, Spring 1995 (Binder 7, Folder 5)
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, October-November 1995 (Binder 5, Folder 11)
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, October-November 1995 (Binder 8, Folder 1)
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, October-November 1995 (Binder 16, Folder 22)
  - Oliver!, Spring 1996 (Binder 6, Folder 1)
  - Oliver!, Spring 1996 (Binder 8, Folder 2)
  - Steel Magnolias, Summer 1996 (Binder 6, Folder 2)
  - Steel Magnolias, Summer 1996 (Binder 8, Folder 3)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, October 1996 (Binder 6, Folder 3)
  - The Skin of Our Teeth, October 1996 (Binder 8, Folder 4)
  - Pippin, 1997 (Binder 8, Folder 5)
  - Biloxi Blues, Summer 1997 (Binder 6, Folder 4)
  - Biloxi Blues, Summer [June] 1997 (Binder 9, Folder 1)
  - Fiddler on the Roof, October 1997 (Binder 9, Folder 2)
  - Getting Out, Spring 1998 (Binder 9, Folder 3)
  - Sylvia, June 1998 (Binder 9, Folder 4)
  - Sweeny Todd, November 1998 (Binder 9, Folder 5)
  - Noises Off, February 1999 (Binder 10, Folder 1)
  - Fifth of July, Summer 1999 (Binder 6, Folder 5)
  - Fifth of July, Summer 1999 (Binder 10, Folder 2)
  - Fifth of July, Summer 1999 (Binder 16, Folder 23)
  - Music Man, Fall 1999 (Binder 10, Folder 3)
  - Two Gentlemen from Verona, Spring 2000 (Binder 10, Folder 4)
  - Waiting for Godot, Summer 2000 (Binder 6, Folder 6)
  - Waiting for Godot, Summer 2000 (Binder 10, Folder 5)
  - Where's Charlie, Winter 2001 (Binder 11, Folder 1)
  - A Lie of the Mind, Summer 2001 (Binder 11, Folder 2)
  - Quilters, Fall 2001 (Binder 11, Folder 3)
  - Major Barbara, February 2002 (Binder 11, Folder 4)
  - Don't Drink the Water, Spring 2002 (Binder 11, Folder 5)
  - Once on the Island, Fall 2002 (Binder 12, Folder 1)
  - The Laramie Project, February 2003 (Binder 12, Folder 2)
  - The Laramie Project, February 2003; 1 disc (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Last Night of Ballyhoo, Summer 2003 (Binder 12, Folder 3)
  - Boy Friend, November 2003 (Binder 12, Folder 4)
  - Night of the Iguana, February 2004 (Binder 12, Folder 5)
  - Blithe Spirt, Summer 2004 (Binder 13, Folder 1)
  - Brigadoon, October 2004 (Binder 13, Folder 2)
  - Brigadoon, October 2004 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Eden Court [and] Beauty Queen, March 3, 2005; 1 disc [ID 580] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Parker Family Circus, June 9, 2005; 1 disc [ID 667] (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Luck Stiff, October 2005; 1 disc [ID 742] (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Lucky Stiff, October 27, 2005; 1 disc (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Angels in America, March 7, 2006; 1 disc 1 of 2 [ID 772] (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Angels in America, March 7, 2006; 1 disc 2 of 2 [773] (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Proof, June 9, 2006; 1 disc [ID 804] (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Midsummer's Night Dream, February 23, 2007; 1 disc [ID 869] (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - A Midsummer's Night Dream, February 23, 2007; 1 disc [ID 870] (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - The Glass Menagerie, June 11, 2007; 1 disc [ID 882] (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - The Glass Menagerie, June 11, 2007; 1 disc [ID 883] (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Carnival, July 31, 2007; 1 disc [ID 858] (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - You Can't Take It With You, October 26, 2007; 1 disc [ID 961] (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - You Can't Take It With You, October 26, 2007; 1 disc [ID 962] (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - South Pacific, February 25, 2008; 1 disc [ID 1002] (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Enchanted April, June 10, 2008; 1 disc [ID 1041] (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Enchanted April, June 10, 2008; 1 disc [ID 1042] (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Merrily, November 4, 2008; 1 disc [ID 1103] (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Almost Maine, March 3, 2009; 1 disc [ID 1035] (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Almost Maine [and] Lughnasa, March 3, 2009; 1 disc [ID 1036] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lughnasa, March 3, 2009; 1 disc [ID 1037] (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - You, The Jury, Novemeber 2017 (Binder 6, Folder 7)
  - Unidentified (Binder 6, Folder 8)
  - Unidentified (Binder 14, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified (Binder 15, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified (Binder 15, Folder 2)
  - Unidentified (Binder 15, Folder 3)
  - Unidentified (Binder 16, Folder 24)
- Videos, II.
  This series of videos of stage productions is arranged in chronological order. Included within the series are Golgonooza one-act performances written and directed by students of the University. N.B. VHS videocassettes have been transferred to DVD format.
  - Oliver!, March 1996; 1.0 videocassette; 2.0 DVD Discs (Box 2, Video 001)
  - Pippin, March 2, 1997; 1.0 videocassette; 2.0 DVD Discs (Box 2, Video 002)
  - Golgonooza 2000, April 15, 2000; 1.0 videocassette; 2.0 DVD Discs (Box 2, Video 003)
  - Golgonooza 2001, 1.0 videocassette; 2.0 DVD Discs (Box 2, Video 004)
  - The Wedding Singer, October 29, 2010; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 005)
  - Clean House, February 2011; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 006)
  - Lend Me a Tenor, October [2011]; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 007)
  - Chicago, March 3, 2012; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 008)
  - Durang/Durang, November 1, 2012; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 009)
  - The Dream Play, October-November 2013; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 010)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, April 2014; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 011)
  - Shadows of Poe, October-November 2014; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 012)
  - Fortinbras, April 4, 2017; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 013)
  - You,The Jury, October 31, 2017; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 014)
  - Fear and Misery in the Third Reich, April 10, 2018; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 015)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, April 3, 2019; 1.0 DVD Disc (Box 2, Video 016)
- Programs, III.
  This series of programs is arranged in chronological order.
  - The Crucible, Winter term 1973; 1. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - West Side Story, February 1973; 2. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - A Trip to Chinatown, October-November 1976; 3. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Passing Through From Exotic Places, March-April 1978; 4. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Kennedy's Children, June 1978; 5. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - The Prime of Miss Jean Brodie, October-November 1978; 6. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - The House of Blue Leaves, February-March 1979; 7. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Mother Courage and Her Children, October 1979; 8. (Binder 17, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - LuAnn Hampton Laverty Oberlander, February 1979; 9. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Merton of the Movies, June 1979; 10. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - A Streetcar Named Desire, October 1980; 1. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - The Cherry Orchard, February 1981; 2. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 4)
  - Bare Boards and Passion, May 1981; 3. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 5)
  - The Journey of the Fifth Horse, October 1981; 4. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 6)
  - The Hot L Baltimore, February-March 1982; 5. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 7)
  - The Comedy of Errors, June 1982; 6. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 8)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, October 1982; 7. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 9)
  - The Robber Bridegroom, November 1983; 8. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 10)
  - Summer and Smoke, February-March 1984; 9. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 11)
  - Table Manners, June 1984; 10. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 12)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, November 1984; 11. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 13)
  - Absurdity and Other Virtues, February-March 1985; 12. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 14)
  - Crimes of the Heart, June 1985; 13. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 15)
  - The Imaginary Invalid, November 1985; 14. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 16)
  - A Cry of Players, February-March 1986; 15. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 17)
  - Wait Until Dark, June 1986; 16. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 18)
  - DA and The Chalk Garden, October-November 1986; 17. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 19)
  - Arms and the Man, February 1987; 18. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 20)
  - Remains, June 1987; 19. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 21)
  - Our Town, October-November 1987; 20. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 22)
  - The Dining Room, February 1988; 21. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 23)
  - The Sea Gull, June 1988; 22. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 24)
  - Tartuffe, October-November 1988; 23. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 25)
  - Boundaries of Tennessee: A Series of Short Plays, February 1989; 24. (Binder 17, Folder 2, Item 26)
  - The Diary of Anne Frank, February 1990; 1. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - The Citizens of Johnstown vs. the South Fork Fishing and Hunting Club, September 1889, May-June 1990; 2. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - The Long Christmas Dinner, June 1990; 3. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Hay Fever, October-November 1990; 4. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 4)
  - Dark of the Moon, February 1991; 5. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 5)
  - Quartermaine's Terms, May-June 1991; 6. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 6)
  - The Tempest, October-November 1991; 7. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 7)
  - Three Sisters, February-March 1992; 8. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 8)
  - Into the Woods, Spring 1995; 9. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 9)
  - The Good Woman of Setzuan, October-November 1995; 10. (Binder 17, Folder 3, Item 10)
  - Lend Me a Tenor, [October] 2011; 11. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Durang/Durang, November 2012; 12. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, February-March 2013; 13. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - The Dream Play, October-November 2013; 14. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Shadows of Poe, October-November 2014; 15. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - The Caucasian Chalk Circle, February-March 2015; 16. (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - All In the Timing, November 2016 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Fortinbras, April 2017 (Box 3, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Red-Eye Festival 24 Hours Later, September 2017 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - You, the Jury, November 2017 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Fear and Misery in the Third Reich, April 2018 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - Robin Hood, November 2018 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Golgonooza 2019, February 2019 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 12)
  - A Midsummer Night's Dream, April 2019 (Binder 18, Folder 1, Item 13)
- Newspaper Clippings, IV.
  This series of newspaper clippings is arranged in chronological order. The majority of the clippings are not properly labeled with the title of the newspaper from which it was clipped or the date. When possible, a preservation photocopy of the original article was made.
  - Clippings 1970s, 1973-1979 (Binder 19, Folder 3)
  - Clippings 1980s, 1980-1989 (Binder 19, Folder 4)
  - Clippings 1990s, 1990-1994 (Binder 19, Folder 5)
  - Clippings 2010s, 2012 (Binder 19, Folder 6)
- Marketing Materials, V.
  This series of marketing materials is arranged in chronological order and housed by medium type (playbills or postcards).
  - Twelfth Night, October 1977; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - UPJ Theatre 1977-1978 Season Subscription Announcement, 1. (Binder 19, Folder 1, Item 1)
  - Angels in America, February 2006; 2.; 1.0 postcard (Binder 19, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - South Pacific, February 2008; 3.; 1.0 postcard (Binder 19, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - Chicago, March 2012; 1.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 2)
  - One Flew Over the Cuckoo's Nest, February-March 2013; 2.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 3)
  - The Dream Play, October-November 2013; 3.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 4)
  - Much Ado About Nothing, April 2014; 4.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 5)
  - Theatre 2014-2015, 5.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 6)
  - Shadows of Poe, October-November 2014; 6.; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 7)
  - Durang/Durang (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 8)
  - Theatre Department Season 2015-2016, 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 9)
  - Agatha Christie's And Then There Were None, March 2016; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 10)
  - All In the Timing, November 2016; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 11)
  - Fortinbras, April 2017; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 12)
  - You, the Jury, November 2017; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 13)
  - Little Shop of Horrors, November 2017; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 14)
  - Fear and Misery in the Third Reich, April 2018; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 15)
  - Merrily We Roll Along, date unknown; 1.0 playbill (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 16)
  - Robin Hood, November 2018; 1.0 Playbil (Box 3, Folder 1, Item 17)
- Production Notes and Announcements, VI.
  This series of production notes and announcements is arranged in chronological order and housed by medium type.
  - Twelfth Night Properties List, October 1977; 1. (Binder 19, Folder 2, Item 1)
  - Production Credits, 1980/81-1999/2000; 2. (Binder 19, Folder 2, Item 2)
  - UPJ Theatre Productions log by Kathleen M. Sullivan, 1978/1979-1998/1999; 3.; 1.0 Compositions notebook (Binder 19, Folder 2, Item 3)
  - Theatre Fall 2013 Important Dates and Times, 1.0 poster (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 1)
  - Theatre, [Fall 2015-Spring 2016]; 1.0 poster (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 2)
  - Theatre Fall 2016, 1.0 poster (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 3)
  - Theatre Spring 2017 Important Dates, 1.0 poster (Box 3, Folder 3, Item 4)